I would call the word of the.
I'm sitting council for Tuesday, January 21, 2021.
Two public input.
Let's get to personal answers.
We have none.
Three.
Kind of list.
Motion to approve.
Second.
I.
Jones.
Four minutes from the January 7, 2021.
Regular meeting.
Motion to approve.
Second.
I.
Jones.
Park.
Five.
Budget.
Number 25.
That's 14.
You.
Okay.
This does.
Three.
It allows the library to receive in an.
A.
authorize the same matter, these are.
Sorry, annual grant that we give libraries, the share we've got
in 3158 dollars.
And that is based off of the survey data that we have to turn in
in 2024.
So that's why it's the 2024, because it's based off of information
from last year.
I'm going to approve everybody's looking at the head.
I think it's a fifth.
Hi.
Boom.
Orange.
I'm double.
Hi.
Parker.
Thank you.
So to approve or not, read the rendering of the Civic Center
Gem floor with a logo from the Tri-state pool.
Of course, of course, of course.
Chuck.
So you guys are, back in front of the board,
and you're going to call it a co-eat Alan.
You're going to come with a logo for a Tri-time at the city,
just for it.
There's an awesome time in my phone name for ourselves.
This is the 40th.
How many audio was the 66-40 middle?
I thought it was great.
That's the M's more of the specialist school.
We added this as the side.
The center of the work, however, is 10 foot, followed.
But at the end, the original thought that it would be 92 foot,
6-8 long.
I think it was great.
Thank you again.
Great job.
I was just kidding.
I thought it was a 2-2 left before the roll.
What?
No, he said no.
Oh boy.
Once you put it underneath, and then we can build over it.
Nobody'll ever know.
There you go.
That motion to approve.
Second.
Hi.
Thanks.
I'm Parker.
I think you want to say a real work or sorry,
that I had to give props to the lawsuit departments on
given all the help we needed to get this for them.
They are actually going to start to work before Monday.
It's all in front of me.
A huge shout out to Derek and utilities and taking those notes down.
They're using my call, Derek.
You called me on the press.
That's what's happening.
Our call is, we met on the floor.
My question was, do you have something in your arsenal that I can use to think you did?
The next day, you had to put it there and it includes there and fix those things.
A huge shout out to Derek.
Seven.
I was shooting at eight.
Service contract with geocyte and corporate public safety mobile app for the
marketplace department.
Officers not to see $15,000 annually contingent upon submission of all
required contract documents.
I'm out throughout the city manager.
This program of time gets away.
I think about seven years.
Yes.
It's a computer-related dispatch.
It's a safety program that sits ran by central dispatch.
We're all the officers have.
In the EMS, we're at the hotel.
They have access to this on their phones, on their iPads.
If you look.
if the system like in dispatch, I don't know,
some product in this batch, you can see that it's like a map.
It's like a map to have a map.
It's hard and much to have.
It's like Google map.
It'll show where the options are, where the ambulances are.
It also has all the calls on the side.
Went to pay the bill this year and realized that I don't have
the bill is that every December and we pay it.
So we've got a contract.
I'm like a motion to approve.
Second.
I don't want to.
Can I vote for that?
Just abstain.
That's fine.
I can't.
He uses that.
9.
Order 25.
25.
That's 0.
And then the section 5.
That's 6.
Section 5.
That's 27.
That's 28.
Can't get him.
Angel is here.
She's just loaded the weather.
Oh, okay.
I'm sorry.
No.
This is really a housekeeping issue that we've been trying to clean up for months.
You know, I didn't work on this.
I didn't.
I didn't work on this.
The ordinance that we took to the airport board on the 13.
And they're wrecking the nation.
It was pretty good.
So the major changes that you'll see in 526.
It goes from the airport authority board to the airport board, which is now in the advisory board.
There's always been little confusion about that.
Who ran the airport?
The authority.
Or the city.
And this cleans that up.
And by the ordinance they are in advisory board to the city council.
In the next section of the membership.
It brought us the range of where we can get people to join the board.
You've used that to live here or work here.
Now you have to live here on the walk alley or work in on the walk alley.
So that just opens that up.
It was at point people that we had a hard time coming up.
Because of that restriction.
And then on the last one 528 kind of does the same thing.
It just confers that they are advisory board and all recommendations.
That advisors board will be brought to the council.
Second.
Jones, he's dead.
All right.
Barnes, I don't call.
I'm staying.
Parker.
Hi.
No, no, no.
I'm the regional Airport B schedule.
Again, we brought a number of B schedules before you
over the last so many months.
Angelina went out there.
We kind of realized there really wasn't a set B schedule
for a lot of activities that go on out there.
So Angelina reached out to all the local airports,
the airport's grow prior, the native, the kind of see what
we were missing.
The only fees that we had established were fees for
painters.
No, no.
No permits.
No.
Anything else?
Pursing cards.
So this is kind of a baseline that we put together to
get started on these fees.
Then you can see at the bottom of the hand.
Any changes will come before the council.
I want to change.
But we brought this to the airport in 42 and talking to them.
All the places that they fly, they see these fees.
So they were kind of surprised that we had these fees.
And we're still kind of a little bit.
I would sound a lower end of these fees.
According to them.
But it's a great baseline to start out.
So this gives us the established fee schedule.
For anything that may go on at the airport.
Got it out.
Much to proof.
All right.
Jones.
I don't hope.
I'm staying.
Thank you.
11.
Mayor's nomination.
Point.
Kristen.
The glory to the Member of Public Library.
Board turned expire.
12.
27.
Mr.
Jones.
I.
12.
The Mayor's nomination.
The vote.
Jordan doubted it to the Member of Public Library.
Board.
Time to expire.
12.
28.
Motion.
Second.
On.
I want to say thank you to the street department. The roads were fantastic this year on the ice and snow
They got out and they've done a good job that kept ahead of it fast and it really look good
I was out by 7.30 that morning and notice the same thing. So it was
It was good job here. Do you hear in your crew?
I'll just you and your crew. Thank you
Actually, it has a dance coming up. I'm saying we're 13
Hope to see a lot of these faces there
It's going to be our first dance at the new senior center
It's going to be fairly you'll be there. I'll be there. You're going to be there. You're going to be there too. Is this square dance?
It's any kind of dance and you want to do them. There's squares on the ground
And if you go there's a square there. Are you so square?
You'll be the square.
Why hurt stories?
Don't you meet?
But it is coming up on the 13th admission for nonmembers is only going to be five dollars to get in
Members get in free
So if you are interested in becoming a member of the senior home. It's only 25 dollars a year lots of benefits to become a member
Please let me know if you have any questions on that
Major details
on
walking nachos some foods and drinks
There will be purchase
It's going to be decorated to the nines. You're going to want to see this. You're not going to miss it. We do have a DJ
if I love a DJ
Must be DJ's name. Greg Greg
Not DJ Frousal Rock or something like that just Greg
It might be a stage name. It's just Greg Greg
Frousal Rock but he's an excellent referral. So I'm excited. I'm very excited about this one
This is our first event. I can't wait to be there. I get to go because I'm full of four
But and I'm also going to pay to get in. So there's that. I'm going to pay to get in. I am grandmother. Yes
I think you'll be seen here soon. I've given me rights that you have more people don't understand. Sorry. You'll get there soon.
Well said. Hey, you can. We can hold it.
But it is going to be a ton of fun. It's already been a ton of fun working with the seniors and Kevin and Jill and
Yeah, but it's like your teeth. I'm looking forward to hosting a lot more events out there at the senior center.
So people could see what we've really got going on and how much heart has been put into it already and what at the
decision it was to get the city involved with keeping that and preserving that. Our seniors are very valuable
and they need our help and they need our attention. So we can provide a place to help feed them and warm them
and entertain them. I really can be proud of what's already happened and out there. So I really really hope to
There's your personal one, like, for me, for all of you.
Talk to that, Tyler.
Yeah.
I'm going to sit and shop the same night.
So, make sure you're, they'll make sure.
Oh, where you go.
Thanks, Bowman.
Well, you can use your number to do a maintenance for this in case we can.
Yes.
Bless us out there.
You'll be there, too.
All right.
I'll talk to you.
I'll just sleep over.
Miffy.
I heard Carmen wanted to dance with you, Tyler.
She did.
There's just two things real quick.
We've had a lot of calls in it.
The board, as mentioned, they've got a lot of calls for people that are concerned about the
Argo development that's going out.
I'm just letting everybody wear, missing that kind of letter, response.
So, we have documented that we have, may comment on their, air, permit.
Just a couple of things that I brought up.
I actually talked to them in person, too.
But, you know, we have some concern about the amount of water that will be consumed for the facility
from the offer that we currently get our water from.
You know, we are apprehensive about our offer.
We get our water from being polluted from this.
And, you know, the other thing is, you know, the smell of some of the issues that we had.
And then the last slide is asking, hey, we do some kind of public meeting or something.
Because we're going to have a lot of questions.
I don't know.
The board doesn't need, you know, like, what to answer.
You know, we don't know that.
Let's tell you.
I spent about two hours reading about this today.
And I learned the word, utrification.
And that's interesting.
I think there's pros and cons.
And I think it's worth having conversation around after what I read and researched.
And I'm not talking about Facebook.
I didn't.
I'm talking actual research papers about.
Some of the, some of the things that were listed in an email from a gentleman by the name of Tim Perez that went to Steve Bayshore.
He talked about several.
Byproducts of this offer of this process.
Some of those byproducts they mentioned are byproducts of when this.
Fuel is actually burned, so it wouldn't be byproducts of this actual facility.
A couple of them were like ammonia and the sulfur dioxide.
Those are dangerous to the immediate area.
So it's not as big in scariest.
Maybe they made it out to be.
I'm not saying that I'm all pro.
Digesteration or anything.
Some of it's really good stuff, but.
It's not as.
It's worth having deeper conversations about.
I'll just put it that way.
And when I just reach out to the.
You guys that I can we use them kind of.
I'm going to.
So the biggest.
Pro to this whole thing is.
This chicken manure and on all this type of waste goes in if it doesn't go to some place to be processed.
Like this goes into a landfill and creates.
A thousand times the the methane and and other things that.
That go up into the atmosphere.
And it's not as dangerous as it sounds.
So.
I think we probably experienced more smell from the mushroom from than we ever would something like this.
I think a lot of the people that are contacted us are just a lack of knowledge.
It is, in fact, that it was so quick of the comments into this week.
And everybody started learning about this week.
So I think it was a fear factor of not knowing what it is.
So I don't think they did a good job of educating the people on the issue.
I think the people were just kind of scared because I don't know what it is.
I had three different calls on today and you know just more impression I didn't know about, you know.
One of the interesting things about usually when you have some kind of process like this,
where you're processing something and you're creating something,
there's a byproduct that becomes like you can't do anything with it.
This is the opposite of that.
The byproduct that comes out of this is actually fertilizer that you can use.
The way, like I read a dumb-down, layman's version of what this is.
This is basically like a cow stomach and how it processes things and the gas that's coming out is what they use as the bio fuel.
And then the waste that comes out is actually the fertilizer.
So kind of a simple way to look at it, but that's really what it kind of boils down to.
So the room in of the cattle stomach, you know how that works, right?
Yeah, that's what's going on here.
It's interesting, it's a very interesting process.
I know, yeah, I think it's an nerdy problem that I spent two hours reading about it,
but it was a fun and interesting.
I didn't say that.
The second thing I have is that we've asked for in the quarrel.
So I'll put on the CBB office until we hire somebody to run a full time.
So I can turn to it as excited.
I've just got a boot, a big slice today, ask your house.
You know what I mean?
What I mean?
I'm really excited about it.
So you're going to get fixed and move forwards on it.
I'm really excited about that.
I see a lot of things that we need to improve and something to improve.
This may well be now to be continued from Calstraper's rate to me.
It's natural for purpose of the executive sector.
You said you did believe?
No, it's decent.
You want to be straight down.